Guide to the Michael Grumley Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings and Drawings, 1963-1987; Series II; 7.5; (7 boxes)
  - Other Writings and Drawings
    - "A Medical A B C," with illustrations, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 271)
    - "Mirror Negative," in Cheshire, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 272)
    - "Myth-Anne", 1968 (Box 10, Folder 273-276)
    - "The Object", undated (Box 10, Folder 277)
    - "Once," with illustrations, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 278)
    - The Others, by Robert Ferro: dust jacket illustration, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 279)
    - Pierpont Morgan Library: paper bags, undated (Box 10, Folder 280)
      [Design possibly created by Grumley?]
    - "Rathead", circa 1968 (Box 10, Folder 281)
    - "A Relationship", undated (Box 10, Folder 282)
    - "Roman Pictures" / "Roman Stories", 1986, undated (Box 10, Folder 283-286)
    - "Rose", undated (Box 10, Folder 287)
    - "Sand Rabbits", undated (Box 10, Folder 288)
    - [Sistus IV project], 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 289-290)
      Includes a copy of Two Loaf Givers, by Leonard N. Beck (1984)
    - "Squiggle and Squeak", undated (Box 11, Folder 291)
    - "The Sun Shines in Central Park", 1984 (Box 11, Folder 292)
    - "T is the Tear," with illustrations, undated
    - "Upstairs", undated (Box 11, Folder 293)
    - "The Way of the Animals", undated (Box 11, Folder 294)
    - What Dillinger Meant to Me, by Robert Peters: illustration, [1983]
    - "Whose Zoo?", 1975 (Box 11, Folder 295)
    - "A World of Men"
      - Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 11, Folder 296)
      - "Original copy", undated (Box 11, Folder 297)
      - Drafts, undated (Box 11, Folder 298-312)
    - "Zig-Zag:" treatment for a screenplay, by Michael Grumley and Alex Gotfryd, undated (Box 11, Folder 313-315)
    - Miscellaneous writings and fragments
      - "Writings and drawings 1960s" (Box 11, Folder 316)
      - "Poetry", 1963-1976, undated (Box 11, Folder 317)
      - "1965 writings and artifacts", 1965, undated (Box 11, Folder 318)
      - "College themes and stories", 1966-1967, undated (Box 11, Folder 319-322)
      - "Vonnegut" essays, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 323)
      - "Slater Reviews", undated (Box 12, Folder 324)
      - Notebook, undated (Box 12, Folder 325)
      - Notebook, 1974, undated (Box 12, Folder 326)
      - Notebook, 1988, undated (Box 12, Folder 327)
      - Miscellaneous manuscript and typescript pages, fragments, and notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 328-338)
    - Miscellaneous drawings and collages, 1966-1968, undated (Box 12, Folder 339-340)
- Other Papers, 1971-1988; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  Organized into two subseries: Subject Files, and Writings of Others
  The series primarily contains files of clippings kept by Grumley, which cover topics of personal and professional interest. Some relate to his published writings and supplement those filed in Series II. Writings by Others contains a photocopy of a work by fellow VQ author Andrew Holleran, and a set of files for a project Grumley was working on, as a ghostwriter, with his personal physician; it is unclear how much of the writing was done by Grumley.
  - Subject Files
    - Anthropology / archeology, 1971-1986
    - Copyright, 1971-1977 (Box 13, Folder 341)
    - Crypto zoology, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 342)
    - Czech music and culture, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 343)
    - Health concerns, 1980-1983, undated (Box 13, Folder 344)
    - Homosexuality, 1975-1987
    - Italian art, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 345)
    - Mars, 1976
    - Museums, 1973-1974
    - Primates, 1972-1987, undated (Box 13, Folder 346)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1988
  - Writings by Others
    - Corcos, Josue M., "Acupuncture Today", 1974 (Box 13, Folder 347-349)
      Grumley served as ghost-writer
    - Holleran, Andrew, "The Dancer from the Dance," bound photocopy of typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 350)
- Oversize, 1.2; (5 boxes)
  - Business handwriting certificate (in Series I), 1953 (Box 14, Folder 351)
  - Horoscope, tarot, and numerology readings (in Series I), 1976-1983 (Box 14, Folder 352)
  - New York World's Fair (in Series I), 1964 (Box 14, Folder 353-354)
  - New York Native: portfolio (in Series II), 1980-1984 (Box 14, Folder 355)
  - New York Native: tear sheets (in Series II), 1981-1985, undated (Box 14, Folder 356-361)
  - New York Native: photocopies of tear sheets (in Series II), undated (Box 14, Folder 362)
  - Philadelphia Gay News (in Series II), 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 363)
  - Atlantis: Turolla, Pino (in Series II), 1970, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 364)
  - Atlantis: research materials, expedition notes, miscellaneous articles (in Series II), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 365)
  - Atlantis: book excerpt in Chicago Tribune Sunday Magazine (in Series II), 1971 Feb 14 (Box 15, Folder 366)
  - There Are Giants in the Earth: research materials, printed (in Series II), 1971-1987 (Box 15, Folder 367)
  - "The Adventures of a Chair," illustrations (in Series II), undated (Box 15, Folder 368)
  - "Beach Book" / "Beach Rites": research materials (in Series II), 1980-1981, undated (Box 15, Folder 369-376)
  - Hard Corps: camera copy (in Series II), 1977 (Box 16, Folder 377)
  - Hard Corps: mechanicals (in Series II), 1977 (Box 16, Folder 378-382)
  - Hard Corps: publicity (in Series II), 1977 Mar 14 (Box 16, Folder 383)
  - "Brothers" / "Brothering" (in Series II), 1981-1983 (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - "Cybernetta," with illustrations (in Series II), undated (Box 17, Folder 385)
  - "The Enchanted Garden" / "The Healing Garden," with illustrations (in Series II), 1973, undated (Box 17, Folder 386-388)
  - [Sistus IV project] (in Series II), 1986 (Box 17, Folder 389)
  - "T is the Tear," with illustrations (in Series II), undated (Box 17, Folder 390)
  - What Dillinger Meant to Me, by Robert Peters: illustration (in Series II), [1983] (Box 17, Folder 391)
  - Miscellaneous drawings and collages (in Series II), 1966-1968, undated (Box 17, Folder 392-397)
  - Subject files: Anthropology/archeology (in Series III), 1971-1986 (Box 18, Folder 398-399)
  - Subject files: Homosexuality (in Series III), 1975-1987 (Box 18, Folder 400)
  - Subject files: Italian art (in Series III), 1986-1987 (Box 18, Folder 401)
  - Subject files: Mars (in Series III), 1976 (Box 18, Folder 402)
  - Subject files: Museums (in Series III), 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 403)
  - Subject files: Primates (in Series III), 1972-1986 (Box 18, Folder 404)
  - Subject files: Miscellaneous (in Series III), 1971-1988 (Box 18, Folder 405-409)
  - Writings of Others: Corcos, Josue M., "Acupuncture Today" (in Series III), 1974 (Box 18, Folder 410)